Guide to the John B. Snook Architectural Records Collection 1762-1948 PR 64
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Architectural Drawings, 1846-1948
  - Hyde Park Presbyterian Church, Church Educational Building, Tampa, FL Project #208, 1948 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - Broadway and 22nd Street, New York, NY Project #209, 1899 (Box 34, Folder unknown container)
  - P.A. Fogerty Estate, Stable, Spring Street and Elizabeth Street, New York, NY Project #210, 1896 (Box 35, Folder unknown container)
  - Kacht & Steel, 890-892 Broadway, New York, NY Project #211 (Box 36, Folder unknown container)
  - Hoffmann, Store, 258 Broadway, New York, NY Project #212 (Box 37-38, Folder unknown container)
  - 381 Madison Street, New York, NY Project #213, 1895 (Box 39, Folder unknown container)
  - 143 Broadway, New York, NY Project #214 (Box 39, Folder unknown container)
  - Bank Street and Wall Street, New York, NY Project #215 (Box 39)
  - Alfred Wagstaff, 591 Broadway, New York, NY Project #216 (Box 39)
    General
    See: Folder 17
  - M. Kemper, Tenement, 179 East Broadway, New York, NY Project #217 (Box 39)
    See: Folder 18
  - Tenement, 248 Mulberry Street, New York NY Project #218, 1885 (Box 39)
    See: Folder 19
  - 59 Spring Street, New York NY Project #219 (Box 39)
    See: Folder 20
  - Broome Street and Mulberry Street, New York, NY Project #220, 1884 (Box 39)
    See: Folder 21
  - Motor Freight Terminal, 160 Bank Street, New York, NY Project #221 (Box 39)
    See: Folder 22
  - All Angels' Church, New York, NY Project #222 (Box 39)
    See: Folder 23
  - A.T. Stewart, Store, Broadway at Reade Street, New York, NY Project #223, 1846 (Box 39)
    See: Oversize Folder 26
  - Benjamin Tredwell, Store, 8 College Place, New York, NY Project #224, 1859 (Box 39)
    See: Oversize Folder 27
  - NY & Harlem RR, NY Central RR, and Cornelius Vanderbilt, Grand Central Station, New York, NY Project #225, 1869 (Box 39)
    See: Oversize Frame
  - Architectural Drawings, cont.
    Scope and Contents
    The following drawings have been flattened and are stored in folders.
    - Joseph F. Loubat Stores, 503-511 Broadway, New York, NY Project #19, 1878 (Folder 1-3)
    - Robert James Livingston, Store, 184 Fifth Avenue, New York, NY Project #30, 1873 (Folder 4)
    - Tenement, 244-246 Mulberry Street, New York, NY Project #40, 1885 (Folder 5-6)
    - Roderick Green, Tenement, 64 Oliver Street, New York, NY Project #43, 1889 (Folder 7)
    - 65-67 Watt Street and 12-14 Desbrosses Street, New York, NY Project #51 (Folder 8)
    - Storm Estate, House, Broadway and Reade Street (SW corner), New York, NY Project #81, 1871 (Folder 9)
    - Herman Heidgard, Store, Grand Street and Elm Street, New York, NY Project #98, 1889 (Folder 10)
    - Jacob Korn, Tenements, Henry Street west of Clinton Street, New York, NY Project #102, 1874 (Folder 11)
    - 134-138 West 39th Street, New York, NY Project #145, 1900 (Folder 12)
    - Bank Street and West Street, New York, NY Project #149 (Folder 13)
    - Lewis, 623 Broadway and 190 Mercer Street, New York, NY Project #153, 1881 (Folder 14)
    - Centre Street and Worth Street, New York, NY Project #158, 1889 (Folder 15)
    - Lewis, 31-33 Mercer Street, New York, NY Project #182 (Folder 16)
    - Alfred Wagstaff, 591 Broadway, New York, NY Project #216 (Folder 17)
    - M. Kemper, Tenement, 179 East Broadway, New York, NY Project #217 (Folder 18)
    - Tenement, 248 Mulberry Street, New York NY Project #218, 1885 (Folder 19)
    - 59 Spring Street, New York NY Project #219 (Folder 20)
    - Broome Street and Mulberry Street, New York, NY Project #220, 1884 (Folder 21)
    - Motor Freight Terminal, 160 Bank Street, New York, NY Project #221 (Folder 22)
    - All Angels' Church, New York, NY Project #222 (Folder 23)
    - Rutherford Stuyvesant, Tenement, 196-198 Third Avenue, New York, NY Project #121 (Folder 28)
  - OVERSIZE Architectural Drawings
    - Apartment Building, Madison Avenue at 59th Street, New York, NY Project #38 (Folder 24)
    - 337-341 Canal Street and 7-9 Greene Street, New York, NY Project #155, 1868 (Folder 25)
    - A.T. Stewart, Store, Broadway at Reade Street, New York, NY Project #223, 1846 (Folder 26)
    - Benjamin Tredwell, Store, 8 College Place, New York, NY Project #224, 1859 (Folder 27)
    - NY & Harlem RR, NY Central RR, and Cornelius Vanderbilt, Grand Central Station, New York, NY Project #225, 1869 (Folder unknown)
      This drawing is stored in an oversize frame
- Series II: Financial Records, 1860-1893
  Series II. Business Records includes 37 bound volumes, all but one are some form of financial and business records. One bound "Index to drawings by John B, Snook and John B. Snook & Sons" lists projects and drawings, but it can be difficult to match these to the projects for which drawings are available.
  - ACCOUNT BOOKS
    - John B. Snook 1860-1862 1862-1864 1864-1886 1868-1877 1877-1887 (Folder unknown)
    - John B. Snook & Sons 1887-1893 (2 volumes) (Folder unknown)
  - CONTRACT BOOKS
    - John B. Snook 1843-1855 1855-1873 1873-1882 1883-1887 (Folder unknown)
    - John B. Snook & Sons 1886-1892 1892-1897 (Folder unknown)
  - DAYBOOKS
    - John B. Snook & Sons 1887-1889 1889-1891 1891-1893 1894-1896 1896-1902 1902-1910 (Folder unknown)
  - LEDGERS
    - John B. Snook 1845-1852 1850-1869 1861-1866 1866-1882 1883-1899 (Folder unknown)
    - John B. Snook & Sons 1887-1894 undated (Folder unknown)
  - RECEIPTS & EXPENDITURES
    - John B. Snook & Sons 1865 July 6 - 1866 October 31 1866 November 1 - 1868 July 31 1868 October 1 - 1870 December 31 1871 January 3 - 1873 September 30 1873 October 1 - 1876 July 27 1876 August 1 - 1879 April 26 1879 May 1 - 1881 December 31 1882 January 3 - 1884 April 30 1884 May 1 - 1885 October 1 1885 October 1 - 1888 August 1 (Folder unknown)
  - INDEX TO DRAWINGS
    - Drawings by John B. Snook and John B Snook & Sons, prior to 1901 (Folder unknown)
- Series III: Printed Material from Snook's Library, 1762-1928
  This series includes volumes from the libraries of John Butler Snook and his descendents. Many of the items are fragile and/or damaged. The copies of "Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection" are in very poor condition.
  - Books in English, 1762-1928
    - The Mansions of England in the Olden Time, Vols. I-IV, by Joseph Nash, 1869 (Offsite-box 43)
    - A Dictionary of Architecture, Vols. 1-3, by Robert Stuart, 1854 (Offsite-box 40)
    - Letters of an Architect from France, Italy, and Greece, Vols. I-II, by Joseph Woods, 1828 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Art Studies in Nature as Applied to Design, by J. Glaisher, et al, 1872 (Offsite-box 40)
    - A Treatise on the Decorative Part of Civil Architecture, Vol. II, by William Chambers, 1825 (Offsite-box 41)
    - The Architectural Reprint, 8 Volumes, 1903-1904 (Offsite-box 43)
    - A Century in Construction, James Stewart and Company, publisher, 1944 (Offsite-box 42)
    - The Antiquities of Athens, by James Stuart and Nicholas Revett, 1762 (Offsite-box 57)
    - Designs for Carving and Gilding, by Thomas King, 1830-1850 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Designs for Cottage and Villa Architecture, by Samuel H. Brooks, 1839 (Offsite-box 41)
    - The Architect, Vol. IX, Jan-June 1873 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Elementary Principles of Carpentry, by Thomas Tredgold, 1820 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Open Timber Roofs of the Middle Ages, by D. Bogue, 1849 (Offsite-box 46)
    - The Parthenon Naos, by Ernest Flagg, 1937 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Missouri's Contribution to Architecture, by John Asbury Bryan, 1928 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Villa And Cottage Architecture, Blackie and Sons, publisher, 1868 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Historical Account of the Glasgow Cathedral, by J. Collie, 1836 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Artists' Homes, by Maurice B. Adams, 1883 (Offsite-box 51)
    - The Cathedrals of the World, Vols.1-2, by Fred H. Allen, 1886 (Offsite-box 51)
    - The Architecture of M. Vitruvius Pollio, translated by William Newton, 1791 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Reliques of Ancient English Architecture, by John Johnson, 1858 (Offsite-box 52)
    - The Terra-Cotta Architecture of North Italy, by Lewis Gruner, 1867 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Examples of Carved Oak Woodwork of the 16th and 17th Centuries, by William Bliss Sanders, 1883 (Offsite-box 53)
    - English Interior Woodwork, by Henry Tanner, 1903 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Churches and Royal Monasteries of Batalhas, by Luis De Sousa and James Murphy, 1836 (Offsite-box 57)
    - Later Renaissance Architecture in England, Vols. I-III, by John Belcher and Mervyn E. Macartney, 1897-1901 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Later Renaissance Architecture in England, Vols. IV-VI, by John Belcher and Mervyn E. Macartney, 1897-1901 (Offsite-box 55)
    - Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection, George Barrie, publisher (2 volumes), 1883-1884 (Offsite-box 58)
    - Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection, George Barrie, publisher (2 volumes), 1883-1884 (Offsite-box 59)
    - Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection, George Barrie, publisher (2 volumes), 1883-1884 (Offsite-box 60)
    - Picturesque and Descriptive Views of the City of Dublin by James Malton, 1791 (Offsite-box 56)
    - Plans, Elevations and Sections of Buildings Public and Private, Executed in England, by David Laing, 1818 (Offsite-box 50)
    - History of Woburn Abbey, by P.F. Robinson, 1833 (Offsite-box 56)
  - Books in French, 1812-1872
    - Traite de Construction Appliquee a L'Architecture Civile, by J.A. Borgnis, 1840 (Offsite-box 47)
    - L'Architecture Privee au XIX Siecle, Vols. 1-3, by Cesar Daly, 1864 (Offsite-box 49)
    - L'Architecture Privee au XIX Siecle, Vols. 1-3, by Cesar Daly, 1872 (Offsite-box 48)
    - Motifs Historiques D'Architecture et De Sculpture D'Ornement Vols.1-2, by Cesar Daly, 1871 (Offsite-box 47)
    - Eglises de Bourgs et Villages, by A. Baudot, 1867 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Recueil D'Architecture Civile, by J. Ch. Krafft, 1812 (Offsite-box 57)
  - Books in German, 1840-1887
    - Architektonischen Ordnungen de Griechen und Romer, by J.M. Mauch, 1872 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Die Bauformen des Mittelalters in Sandstein by Adolph Opderbecke, 1882 (Offsite-box 47)
    - Tektonik der Hellenen, by Karl Boetticher, 1873 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Vorlegeblatter fur Maurer und Zimmerleute: Nachtrage in 37 Lithographierten Tafeln mit Erlauterungen Entworfen, by Gustav Stier, 1844 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Architektonische Entwurfe zu Pracht- und Civil-Gebauden, by Bartels, Bauer, et al, 1846 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Archiv fur Natur, Kunst, Wissenschaft, und Leben, by Ochme & Muller, 1840-1842 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Architektonisches Skizzen-Buch (5 bound volumes plus 11 issues), by Ernst and Korn, 1855-1876 (Offsite-box 45)
    - Potsdam, by F. Riegel, 1842 (Offsite-box 56)
    - Decorativer Ziegelbau, by Hermann Bethke, 1887 (Offsite-box 50)
  - Books in Italian, 1826-1840
    - La Casa di Delizia, by Alessandro Gherardesca, 1826 (Offsite-box 49)
    - Capitolo, by A. Desgodetz, circa 1840 (Offsite-box 53)